[
  {
    "intro": "I'm a butler, can I butel you?",
    "question": "will you let him butle",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "yaaayyyy",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -100
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "boooo",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "I'm the finest traveling horse salesman around and I have just the horse for you! Just don't check its mouth...",
    "question": "Would you like to buy the salesman's horse?",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "Pleasure doing business with ya!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "give_horse",
            "value": "random"
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -800
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "Suit yourself! It's your loss!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "Psst, your horse is looking a little weak. I've got just the thing for that",
    "question": "Will you accept steroids for one of your horses?",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "Very wise! If you're not cheating you're not trying",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "change_speed",
            "value": 10
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_stamina",
            "value": 10
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_acceleration",
            "value": 10
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_fertility",
            "value": -30
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -500
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "What's wrong? Not a fan of the juice?",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "Wow, What a horse! I'll give you a fair price to take it off your hands?",
    "question": "Would you like to sell one of your horses?",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "Pleasure doing business with ya!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "take_horse",
            "value": "random"
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": 1000
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "agggghh! Fine! Have it your way!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "Oh no! it looks like someone left the barn door open! All the horses got out!",
    "question": "We don't have much time! Quick, should we check by the river first?",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "They weren't by the river! You found them eventually but it seems like one ran off...",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "take_horse",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "You checked in the pasture instead and found them all! Thank goodness!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "Oh no! it looks like someone left the barn door open! All the horses got out!",
    "question": "Quick, should we look near the woods first?",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "You found them all! thank goodness!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "They weren't there... you found them eventually but it looks like one ran off...",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "take_horse",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "I'm a doctor from the city! I recently found developed a technique to increase your horses fertility! interested?",
    "question": "Would you like to pay the doctor $1000 to treat your horse?",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "There you go! happy breeding!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "change_fertility",
            "value": 20
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -1000
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "Bah! Why would your reject the wonders of modern science??",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "intro": "I've come up with a new training routine, its pretty intense but works well!",
    "question": "Would you like to have him train one of your horses? It will tire them out and cost $1000",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "No Pain! No Gain! Let's Go!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -1000
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_speed",
            "value": 20
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_energy",
            "value": -100
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "Lame! Guess you don't have what it takes to be a winner",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
   {
    "intro": "I've come up with a new training routine, its pretty intense but works well!",
    "question": "Would you like to have him train one of your horses? It will tire them out and cost $1000",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "No Pain! No Gain! Let's Go!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -1000
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_acceleration",
            "value": 20
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_energy",
            "value": -100
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "Lame! Guess you don't have what it takes to be a winner",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  },
   {
    "intro": "I've come up with a new training routine, its pretty intense but works well!",
    "question": "Would you like to have him train one of your horses? It will tire them out and cost $1000",
    "choices": {
      "yes": {
        "response": "No Pain! No Gain! Let's Go!",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "change_money",
            "value": -1000
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_stamina",
            "value": 20
          },
          {
            "effect": "change_energy",
            "value": -100
          }
        ]
      },
      "no": {
        "response": "Lame! Guess you don't have what it takes to be a winner",
        "effects": [
          {
            "effect": "nothing",
            "value": "random"
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  }

]